<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <atom:link href="http://capitol-seo.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <link>http://capitol-seo.com/</link>
    <description></description>
    <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2016 21:47:26 -0700</pubDate>
    
      <item>
        <title>Meta Description Tips</title>
        <link>http://capitol-seo.com/2016/10/18/meta-description-tips.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://capitol-seo.com/2016/10/18/meta-description-tips.html</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Meta tags are very important in the search optimization world. These are the first signals to search engines that advise what the site is about. One meta tag in particular, the meta description, is a key component of a successful online campaign. It must be filled out correctly if you want it to have the maximum effect for your site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The meta description tag is the little blurb that shows under the URL line in a search engine result. It is the first piece of content that potential visitors see when they pull up the results. As such, you need to make sure it is accurate, intriguing, and enticing enough for the user to click through.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meta descriptions are limited to 160 characters. This is not a lot of space to play around with. You will need to be creative and concise at the same time. Some good rules to follow are the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use an active voice - This inspires action on the user’s behalf. It also makes the description sound fresh and exciting.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Don’t click bait - Promising things in the meta description that people can’t really find on the site will make your bounce rate high. This is bad!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use your targeted keyword - Your meta description should have your keyword somewhere in it. This will help identify what your site is about.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tell the user what to do - Is is a great idea to tell a user how to benefit from using your site. A simple “learn more here” or “contact us today” tells the user what you want them to do with the information. It also makes it seem like a real person is behind the website.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use structured content if applicable - If you sell products, it’s a good idea to use structured content to give specific info about your product. People might want to know if the page will be about a specific model number, or is offered at a certain price.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take time with your meta description so that people get the best first impression about your site. It’s really your first and only chance to get someone to check out your website. Don’t alienate potential visitors. Engage them on the spot so they will want to choose your site over all the others listed!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Penguin Has Bite</title>
        <link>http://capitol-seo.com/2016/10/17/Penguin-Has-Bite.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://capitol-seo.com/2016/10/17/Penguin-Has-Bite.html</guid>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;penguin-40-can-kill-the-good-with-the-bad&quot;&gt;Penguin 4.0 Can Kill the Good with the Bad&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When &lt;a href=&quot;http://capitol-seo.com/2016/09/23/penguin-4.0-update.html&quot;&gt;Penguin 4.0&lt;/a&gt; first came out (just a week or so ago) it looked promising. At first glance, it seemed like it could be a pretty fair update. First, it was said to be granular, meaning that only specific pages would be affected if link manipulation occurred. Second, it was said to devalue instead of demote like Panda does. Overall, it seemed like it might not be too bad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that a little time has passed we are learning what Penguin is really about. At his latest appearance on the 3rd day of pubcon, Gary Illyes talked about a few things worth mentioning. One of these is the idea that Penguin can effectually demote a site if given the reason to. Illyes stated that where there appears to be a pattern of link manipulation, the G-Team can devalue all the links in one fell swoop. Talk about throwing out the baby with the bathwater!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far it is unclear whether the “mass devaluation” will occur on the affected url or the site as a whole. We suppose that the granular effect of Penguin 4.0 would limit it to the url in question. Either way, it is a scary thing to think about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-invitation-to-negative-seo&quot;&gt;The Invitation to Negative SEO&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Penguin 4.0 seemed to resolve one big problem that occurs in the search optimization field: negative SEO. This concept involves one competitor intentionally spamming the site of another in order to prompt a penalty. Doing so would basically get the competition out of the way so that one’s site could occupy a higher position in the rankings. Penguin 4.0’s use of devaluation instead of demotion made it a lot harder to &lt;em&gt;neg SEO&lt;/em&gt; someone because the extra links would basically be valueless instead of penalty inducing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, it seems that someone could &lt;em&gt;neg SEO&lt;/em&gt; a site and trick G into thinking that the site owner is doing it. Theoretically, in this scenario G could devalue all the sites links, even the powerful ones that are maintaining the site’s ranking. Obviously, this would send the site into search engine limbo. We suppose the &lt;a href=&quot;https://support.google.com/webmasters/answer/2648487?hl=en&quot;&gt;disavow tool&lt;/a&gt; could still come in handy here, but who knows to what extent and when. Furthermore, the fact that Penguin 4.0 runs in real time means that your site could get dumped even before you get a chance to react.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;summary&quot;&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What we can take from this is that black hat SEO is a real gamble with today’s version of Penguin. We also note that webmasters must continually monitor their sites for suspicious activity from unknown sources. We don’t know the full story about this yet, but it sure is a wake-up call for anyone concerned about their site’s well-being.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Dawn of the Mobile Search Index</title>
        <link>http://capitol-seo.com/2016/10/17/Googles-new-mobile-index.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://capitol-seo.com/2016/10/17/Googles-new-mobile-index.html</guid>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;google-will-soon-release-a-primary-mobile-search-index&quot;&gt;Google Will Soon Release a Primary Mobile Search Index&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all, this is huge news! G plans on creating another whole search index that will be served to mobile devices. This means that there will be two versions of the tech giant’s search index: the old desktop version, and the new mobile version. Very soon we might began to see different search results depending on the medium you are using!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-mobile-index-says-who&quot;&gt;A Mobile Index? Says Who?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The news came direclty from Gary Illyes during his &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pubcon.com/keynote-gary-illyes-pubcon-las-vegas-2016&quot;&gt;keynote speech at Pubcon&lt;/a&gt; in Las Vegas. Gary explained that in the current situation, G ranks sites in the mobile search index based on their ranking signals in the desktop version. This apparently created some problems as many mobile sites are not structured the same as their desktop counterparts. Illyes said that it makes more sense to create a separate index because the index system had problems ranking two sites with identical content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other amazing news related to this topic is that the mobile index will now become Google’s main index! The desktop version will be the “secondary” index, meaning that it will get a little less TLC in terms of updates and refreshes. The reason for the big switch is that 85% of searches are now being made from mobile devices. Thus, it makes sense for G to focus on the more popular method of searching. However, this is not all the news we got. To top it all off, Illyes mentioned that the dawn of this new index is just months away! This means that we could be using this index in early 2017 whenever we search from a smartphone or tablet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-this-means-for-the-average-webmaster&quot;&gt;What This Means for the Average Webmaster&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have a personal website or a site for your business, you’ll need to step up your mobile game! The new index will likely run on a different type of algorithim than the desktop version. As such, it will count a different set of signals in order to figure out which sites should be ranking at the top. We think the signals used will be something akin to the mobile updates which were deployed on the desktop search version. The last &lt;a href=&quot;https://webmasters.googleblog.com/2016/03/continuing-to-make-web-more-mobile.html&quot;&gt;Google mobile update&lt;/a&gt; that we know of happened somewhere around May of 2016. This update gave a boost to sites that were termed “mobile friendly.” G has since dropped the use of the mobile friendly terminology, perhaps because they are integrating its engine into the new search index.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end, sites will have to be better adapted to the mobile environment. For example, if you are using structured data to produce rich snippets on your main site version, you’re going to want to add it to your mobile site as well. Today, with responsive design at the helm of modern website creation, a desktop site and mobile site are usually one in the same. Yet, all these sites will have to be retrofitted in some way to ensure that they are truly mobile optimized. We can help make sure your site meets the needs the of mobile user. Contact us now to find out how we can mobilize you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ll update you soon when we hear more news about this gigantic change in the SEO landscape. For now, use the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/webmasters/tools/mobile-friendly/&quot;&gt;mobile friendly test&lt;/a&gt; to see if your site meets G’s current mobile standards.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Wordpress.com Becomes More SEO Friendly</title>
        <link>http://capitol-seo.com/2016/10/06/wordpress-new-seo-tools.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://capitol-seo.com/2016/10/06/wordpress-new-seo-tools.html</guid>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;wordpress-has-just-released-advanced-seo-tools&quot;&gt;Wordpress Has Just Released Advanced SEO Tools!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The people over at &lt;a href=&quot;https://automattic.com/&quot;&gt;Automattic&lt;/a&gt; have just made Wordpress all the better! Those how have a wordpress.com business account will now have acces to &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.blog.wordpress.com/2016/10/03/attract-more-visitors-to-your-business-site-with-our-advanced-seo-tools/&quot;&gt;advanced SEO tools&lt;/a&gt; that will help your site rank higher. The new features will make Wordpress.com blogs more like self-hosted sites which use one of the many available plug-ins, such as Yoast. Check out the new features below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;custom-title-tags&quot;&gt;Custom Title Tags&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Title tags might be the most important meta-tag out there. This is the short description (usually 70-71 characters) that shows at the top of the browser bar when you visit a site. If you are confused as to where this is, take a look at the top of our site which should start off with &lt;a href=&quot;https://capitol-seo.com&quot;&gt;“Sacramento SEO Expert…” &lt;/a&gt; This tag is critical to SEO success because search engines often refer to it in order to find out what the page is about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the past, title tags have been abused and subject to over-optimization penalties. Nowadays, it’s a lot smarter to use proper title tags that truly benefit readers of the site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This feature was previously not editable on Wordpress.com sites, and it will bring a big change for the bloggers and website owners that work exclusively on the .com version of WP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;meta-description-controls&quot;&gt;Meta Description Controls&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with title tags, you were not able to edit meta descriptions on previous versions of wp.com. Meta descriptions are the brief explanations that show under the site address in search results. These are great for SEO because they can encompass certain keywords that a site is trying to rank for, and therefore produce better rankings. Formerly, search engines pulled text (from an article) which it thought was relevant to present in the results. Basically, the site owner had no control of how the description would be presented to potential readers. Now, you have the ability to tell readers what you want to about the site, and you can also squeeze in some important terms to get your site in the right search results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;social--search-previews&quot;&gt;Social &amp;amp; Search Previews&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another really cool feature is the ability to view how your site will look in search and social listings. This will help site owner see their site from another perspective and modify it to their liking. This makes wp.com much more social friendly than it already is, and provides a much better user experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;why-this-matters&quot;&gt;Why This Matters&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wordpress.com is a great option for people who don’t want to deal with the management invovled in a self-hosted site. Wp.com servers are great, and the fact that they are expertly managed for you (for free) means that you can concentrate on your website instead of dealing with hosting issues. Using Wordpress thorugh the .com site is an ideal scenario for start-ups or small businesses that want to stay secure and efficient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main drawback to Wordpress.com in the past was that one sacrificed control over SEO optimization. That has now changed. I think a lot of new users will be heading down this route due to the ease of use and reliabilty that the .com site offers. If you are interested in this as an option for your site, contact us. We have worked extensively with both Wordpress.com and self-hosted WP sites, and we can get you up and running in no time!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Penguin 4.0 Roll Out</title>
        <link>http://capitol-seo.com/2016/09/23/penguin-4.0-update.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://capitol-seo.com/2016/09/23/penguin-4.0-update.html</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Google has announced that the recent update in the search results is due to the long anticipated Penguin 4.0.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;whats-the-big-deal-about-penguin&quot;&gt;What’s the Big Deal About Penguin&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many web masters and SEO experts have dreaded this update for some time. The Penguin update attacks web spam and black hat web linking schemes. Webmasters who paid for links or used link building software were hit hard by past updates, often losing their rankins for several years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-new-parts-of-penguin&quot;&gt;The New Parts of Penguin&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are some new aspects of Penguin due to the recent update. First, Penguin is now said to be a “real time” algorithm This means that it will check links (and value or devalue as needed) with every crawl and indexation. Hopefully, this means that web pages which have been devalued can get their rankings back faster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A second thing that Penguin 4.0 brings is the granular approach. In the past, a penalty affected the site as a whole. Google’s web spam team now says the effect will be limited to specific webpages which are in violation. This is a more fairer approach to the spamming problem. It also helps ward off negative SEO attacks and leaves a victimized business with the chance to salvage other parts of its website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One more change is that the G team will not be announcing any further Penguin updates. Rather, the update will be absorbed into the core algorithm of the search engine. This means it will continue to run consistently and may have a few small refreshes here and there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-it-all-means&quot;&gt;What It All Means&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far, our team hasn’t noticed much of a change in the search results. There was some dancing and shifting going on early in the month. Google originally said this was not related to the Penguin update, but rather was a set of testing procedures performed on the results. It looks like now that the activity earlier on was related to Penguin in some way, yet the update wasn’t officially released until a day or two ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Usually an update takes a few weeks to fully roll out. We may have to see where this all leads in the next month. We will continue to monitor the situation and inform you of any major changes that come along.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
